<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>All Acting.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 16:35:07 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 16:35:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Red Caravan Presents: RubberMatch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RubberMatch begins with Nina (Meredith Owens) verbalizing the text messages she’s sending to an unknown guest. As she goes through several ritual moments in preparation to receive someone into her DUMBO apartment, we immediately get a feeling for what kind of person she is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Ceci (Kayla Jackmon), an old college girlfriend, puts Nina’s anxieties on high alert, and through the broken communications of these two old friends, an entire world is built. Other friends are discussed, past events are dredged back up into the light, and questions of identity are poked at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest with you, these are not normally themes or ideas I’m remotely interested in while watching a play. Hearing characters talk about events that have occurred offstage feels like something reserved for Shakespeare or the Greeks, something we should’ve theatrically evolved beyond by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, luckily, gorgeously, brilliantly, Paz Pardo’s script has taken this uneasy device and twisted it to maximum effect. All the expositional elements of the dialogue are played as that: dialogue. Despite being a two-hander, the play rarely dips into excess monologuing, and every word of it feels like a conversation you might actually hear or take part in. There’s an easy naturalism to the play, which Andrew Willis-Woodward’s direction highlights and underscores with awkward moments and breaks in connection. It all feels real enough for you to forget a lot of the time that you’re watching two actors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this for me is the play’s strongest showing. Meredith Owens gives us, as Nina, a gorgeous window into a character that is rarely represented so beautifully onstage. If only I could show all my acting teachers her performance, I might never again have to hear another speech about how “quiet characters can’t exist on stage.” Every nervous mannerism, conversational fumble, and quirky ritual is crystal clear, while still giving us plenty of space to learn about a character without beating us over the head with things we have to know. The subtlety of expression Owens employs as Nina is something I wish I could see in every play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutting a complete contrast, Kayla Jackmon slices through the silences as Nina’s polar opposite Ceci. Espousing a brutal ex-boyfriend backstory and dying to get, you know, &lt;em&gt;wasted,&lt;/em&gt; Ceci would be a tough sell for me if Jackmon didn’t bring such energy and fun to the role. Nina only really works with a brilliant counter-balance like Ceci, and Jackmon gives Owens plenty to react to, while also giving the audience her own story. The way she leads the shifting dynamics between the characters to and fro really fills out the play in the moments between the backstory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the two actors truly weave together the disjointed history of ten years prior, when both girls were in college with their two best friends Katie and Lauren. You can actually feel Katie and Lauren’s presence onstage, even though neither of the girls actually show up in the play. The way everything from back then feels related to everything happening onstage now makes the outer narrative instrumental to telling the inner one, and it’s profoundly satisfying to see a story told in this way done so right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The set, which brilliantly emulates a spacious apartment in a trendy Brooklyn neighborhood, grounds the exposition in the here and now. Before the play began, seeing a light cast onstage that perfectly mimicked ambient street light coming in through a huge loft window made me nostalgic for my own apartment, and there’s something very familiar yet completely menacing about the void of the all white apartment the stage has become. Designers Peiyi Wong, Jason Fok, and Cherie A. Roberts set a bar of stylish realism, and the actors look completely at home playing around in it. I’m also pretty overjoyed about the play’s unlikely inclusion of an Elvis tune, but I won’t spoil it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubberMatch manages to strike chords all across the theatrical piano, with uproariously funny moments intertwined with quiet, sweet, and tragic ones as well. Rather than cling to any particular genre rules, it strives first and foremost towards the organic, with moments evolving out of each other in a way that feels both beautiful and desperate. The awkward-comedic tensions of its first half are replaced by a needy anxiety that pulls you in different directions, and the play’s lack of concern for filling in the blanks is what makes it a true joy to watch. The ending, by the way, is masterful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information about Red Caravan, cruise on over to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20160605003538/http://www.redcaravanco.com/&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;. For any followup questions about this review, file ‘em to tim@brashpursuits.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/05/20/red-caravan-rubbermatch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/05/20/red-caravan-rubbermatch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Recommendations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding Your Voice With Jon Stancato</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If my &lt;a href=&quot;/recommendations/2016/02/15/sing-a-secret.html&quot;&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt; about Jon Stancato’s Inside Voice workshop flew you by, consider what you’re about to read a fervent call to action. Hot off the heels of my second foray into Jon’s particular brand of vocal exploration, my entire instrument is buzzing with adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For too long, singing and vocal training have been reduced to an incredibly small box. Do these exercises until you get this result. Take it slow to make sure you don’t hurt yourself. Look at pictures of anatomy and bang your head against the wall until you know exactly how your lungs are doing what they’re doing. Not only is it frustrating if your mind and creativity don’t work that way, it’s flat-out &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;boring&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But three hours of learning to enjoy the voice with Jon go by in a flash. You imagine yourself, for a moment, in the best conservatory the world has to offer. And then you remember that it’s just one guy, doing what he loves because he loves doing it. I have never, and probably will never, be in another room where ten or fifteen people suddenly see and know each other on a completely different level than exists out there in the normal world. Sounds you have never heard before come from the deepest parts of your comrades, and rather than making you feel like you can’t match up, it spurs you on to bigger and bolder places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while the intro class was big and fun and brilliant, the second, slightly more advanced class lead the work into deeper, darker, and more intimate places. In my first three hours with Jon, I heard what sounds were possible. In the second three hours, I started to really explore sounds that were mine and only mine. Here I was also introduced to Dark Breath, a concept from Jon’s Roy Hart background. It is one of the strangest and most difficult to describe things I’ve ever done in an acting studio, but it left me with a completely different connection to breath than I’ve ever had before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also jumped into ensemble work, something I’ve always been dragged into kicking and screaming. It amazed me how easy it was to dive right into working with people whose names I didn’t even know, simply because we had already spent an hour and a half howling and yowling and elating together. There is truly a freedom of the entire being that comes from doing voice-work in this way. When a person can sound out unself-consciously, the rest of the job becomes so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this carried over into my day-to-day dealings as well. I happened to schedule an audition right after the workshop, and while I intellectually wanted to be flustered rushing from one place to the next, my whole being felt so free and easy that it was impossible to really worry about it. It was easy to dive into and also throw away the big dramatic moments expected of me without really worrying if I was “selling it” or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing the work in this way primes you to explore on your own. It allows you to ask the question “What is my voice?” without shame or embarrassment. It helps you, in a completely safe and grounded way, completely test the limits and extremes of what a human voice can be. It reminds you that every line, every sound, every expression can be a great adventure in any direction, one that doesn’t have to be predetermined or judged for its conventional beauty, but rather experienced solely for its rawness and vitality. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels ironic that Alfred Wolfsohn first arrived at this work by hearing the sounds of people dying, when working with Jon has introduced me to what it sounds like to truly be alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sign up for a free Sing A Secret workshop, cruise over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.singasecret.com/&quot;&gt;Jon’s website&lt;/a&gt;. For any questions about my particular experiences working with Jon, direct emails to tim@brashpursuits.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/05/10/finding-your-voice-with-jon-stancato.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/05/10/finding-your-voice-with-jon-stancato.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Recommendations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Science of On-Camera Acting by Andréa Morris</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I picked up a copy of The Science of On-Camera Acting for $7 to read on my phone. The analytical title didn’t totally thrill me, but the low price-point and spotless reviews made me think there must be something beyond the book’s title that made it worth the read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can, with firm confidence, say that The Science Of On-Camera Acting is the best book you can find on film acting. Whether you are a stage actor making the leap to screen, a total newcomer to acting in general, or a seasoned film actor, the book will give you a variety of insights on how to pare down your technique to only the bare essentials, giving the kind of performance that audiences routinely pay higher and higher ticket prices to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the science is what gave me pause about the book in the first place, it is actually what makes the book a profound success. Rather than give too much breadth to things like talent and good looks, Morris talks with absolute and simple precision about the things that WORK on camera. Her argument is that regardless of what a performance feels like, if it doesn’t look right on camera, it doesn’t sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the adjustments she suggests all work toward a framework of good acting. In her book, gone are the useless over-assertions of an analytical approach to acting, cutting scenes up into beats and intellectual scores. Here she explains ways to access truthfully playing yourself, and interesting ways to play a character on-screen without looking like you’re acting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the wealth of information asserting a certain kind of acting work, which worked primarily onstage and primarily 60 years ago, it’s incredibly important that Morris is describing, in great detail, what the work of the actor of TODAY is. If you want to be on film in any capacity, this book is a must read. I would even suggest it for those working behind the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can check out more of ‘s work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.becomingmedia.com/&quot;&gt;www.becomingmedia.com&lt;/a&gt;. Please direct any followup questions about this article to tim@brashpursuits.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/04/06/the-science-of-on-camera-acting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/04/06/the-science-of-on-camera-acting.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Authentic Actor By Michael Laskin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Acting books. We’ve all read one. Every acting class I’ve ever been in has assigned at least one, whether it was a classic source like &lt;em&gt;An Actor Prepares&lt;/em&gt; or something written by the instructor themselves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I must’ve read twenty or thirty books on acting or more. A lot of them repeat and rehash the same old tried and true approach to acting. The spine of a role, actions, beats, et cetera et cetera ad nauseam. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorites though, tend to offer a vastly different approach to acting. They certainly build from the foundations built by Stanislavski and the Group Theater, but they certainly don’t stop there. They take into account the day-by-day advancements of the impossible art form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Laskin’s book &lt;em&gt;The Authentic Actor&lt;/em&gt; is just such an entry into the score of acting literature. In it, Laskin gleefully tosses out ideas and philosophies that, while complementary of the foundational work of the actor, also advocate for a shift in the paradigm. There’s no point, really, in doing all of the homework if it doesn’t result in real, living performance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laskin’s language is so his own that it would be a crime to try and sum the book up here. Really, you can look at the title and know what the book is more or less “about.” But while the book’s thesis is incredibly important, what’s more important is the way Laskin leads you to its conclusion. There’s wit, insight, and a nurturing sense of assurance here. It is one of the only times I’ve ever felt like a book was particularly kind to me, and I don’t mean that it gave me a pat on the back and a gold star just for showing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laskin is honest about the harsh realities of the acting world, but he dispenses equally honest advice on how to navigate that harshness. It isn’t easy to show up and be completely yourself, and it also isn’t easy to write a book on how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Michael Laskin succeeds. I won’t spoil how or why, because I think you simply have to read the book for yourself, but I can assure you that it’s one that belongs on the most perused part of your shelf, to be revisited in times of calm and times of strife. Most spiritual and philosophical acting texts, in their divorce from the pure study of technique, can go far out in their search for a new definition of acting. But &lt;em&gt;The Authentic Actor&lt;/em&gt; sticks with the definition of acting we’ve had since the days of Brando and James Dean, and simply adds the years since, and the insights about what acting is that have come along with them, onto what we already knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the actor, most roads of training lead you to &lt;em&gt;do something&lt;/em&gt; as opposed to &lt;em&gt;being what you are.&lt;/em&gt; Michael Laskin’s book is a necessary look in a different direction, and a joyful one at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information about Michael Laskin, please visit __www.michaellaskinstudio.com&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;For any questions about this article, please reach out to tim@brashpursuits.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/03/11/the-authentic-actor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/03/11/the-authentic-actor.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Body of an American</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been trying to frame my experience with The Body of an American since I saw it a few nights ago. I could certainly describe the production from the standard perspective, with questions like “Was the staging interesting?” or “Was the acting good?” Given the subject matter of the play, I could even take the political approach and talk about the themes the play speaks to. It is a play about a war photographer, so it is rife with political thoughts and positions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But covering the standard ground of theatre criticism isn’t particularly interesting to me in the case of this play. For one, I’m not really qualified to say whether this or that element was good or bad. I never see more than five or ten plays a year, so who am I to really say if the play succeeds on this or that level?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I can say is that the play haunted me in much the same way Paul Watson’s Fresh Air interview haunted Dan O’Brien. When I saw the two in person at a talk at Primary Stages, Paul Watson remarked how unlikely it is that the events of his life would line up in such a way that this play was written, and then put on, and that he would end up in that room talking about those things at that moment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This unlikeliness, this existential question, this anxiety about the determination of all things, is what grips me about the play. It’s what keeps me thinking about it, even when I don’t want to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The play is not always a comfortable space to be in. It is shockingly entertaining given its subject matter, but the malady that these two men share, frankly and earnestly, made it very, very difficult for me to contend with. But I think it was important that I did. For possibly the first time ever in the theater, I was able to hear two people ask the questions that I know I’ll never get an answer to. In drama, we routinely have characters who take action, who do not stop to really reflect on what this life actually is. I think this is largely because if the characters don’t take action, and do stop to have long, meandering conversations about “the nature of things” the play becomes boring, navel-gazey, and self-indulgent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow, The Body Of An American doesn’t do that. The play manages to move at times very slowly through a very claustrophobic psychological space, and this makes it horrifying and wonderful instead of tiresome and boring. Perhaps it’s just because everything in the play is true. I really don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m certain that most people’s experience of the play will probably not reflect mine. Most people are more interested in politics than me, most people are more socially conscious and aware of world events. Most people will be able to look at it is “an intriguing play.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, however, will always remember it as two actors performing a ghost story wherein, somehow, I am one of the ghosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is what really moves me about it. This is the kind of thing I hope I’m able to do one day. Plays like this are the reason plays are made. I can’t say any more about it because I very frankly don’t know how, but I think, in fact, that is actually a very good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Body Of An American continues its run at The Cherry Lane Theater from now until March 20th. For more information about the play, and more details about all the brilliant people involved, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://primarystages.org/shows/current-season/the-body-of-an-american&quot;&gt;http://primarystages.org/shows/current-season/the-body-of-an-american&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/02/26/the-body-of-an-american.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/02/26/the-body-of-an-american.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sing A Secret: A Vocal Workshop With Jon Stancato</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a complicated relationship with my voice. It rarely, if ever, does exactly what I want it to. I could write an entire blog post, if not a whole book, about my particular vocal hangups. But today, I don’t have to, because I recently attended Jon Stancato’s workshop, called Sing A Secret, and I left it feeling, for the first time in a long time, a different sensation when I speak and sing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the workshop, which is currently free because Jon is a literal angel, Jon takes singers, actors, and even people who have never considered themselves singers before through a series of exercises over the course of three hours. Over the course of my life, I’ve taken a lot of classes in a three hour format, but rarely, if ever has three hours flown by so quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon is the rare teacher who can combine gentle attention, concentration, and fun in a way that challenges you to step outside of your comfort zone without really feeling like he’s challenging you to do anything at all. Drawing from acting and voice teachers before him (specifically &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.folkways.si.edu/vox-humana-alfred-wolfsohns-experiments-in-extension-of-human-vocal-range/contemporary-electronic-science-nature-sounds/album/smithsonian&quot;&gt;Alfred Wolfsohn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roy-hart-theatre.com/site/the-voice-work/&quot;&gt;Roy Hart,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://richardarmstrong.info/&quot;&gt;Richard Armstrong,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Towards-Poor-Theatre-Routledge-Paperback/dp/0878301550&quot;&gt;Jerzy Grotowski,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theworkcenter.org/&quot;&gt;Thomas Richards&lt;/a&gt;), we went through an arsenal of exercises that included rolling on the floor, playing silly characters, and  a lot of other things that to an outsider wouldn’t seem to have any real bearing on one’s ability to sing beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is where Jon’s workshop is fundamentally different from any voice lesson I’ve ever received. There is much less attention given towards any perceived goal, and more attention towards exploring, and even enjoying particular sounds as sensations, regardless of how good they sound. This freed up everyone in the room to sing at their most expressive, regardless of their individual training and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough can’t be said for the environment. I always show up to these things with a lot of anxiety about the classroom as a whole, expecting everyone to be more skilled than me. But that’s simply not the environment here. Because of the specificity of the technique no comparisons can be made between students, even if you’re like me, and constantly judging yourself based on what everyone else is doing. There’s a deeply uplifting energy, and the success of others makes you want to go after your own expression more, rather than set yourself up for failure. I’ll admit, I was as self-conscious as I’ve ever been in this class, but it provides a real space to understand that there’s simply no reason to be. Jon creates an environment where artists are free to explore, and “failure” feels like it doesn’t even really exist in the walls of his classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s truly an amazing experience just watching Jon coach a singer. He can see and hear things in very subtle ways, and make very minor shifts to massive effect. He hones in on one particular detail that catches his attention, but as soon as he calls it out and directs it, entire musical vistas open up for the person singing. And it doesn’t feel, as it sometimes does in acting workshops, that Jon is just a mastermind who can command results. I left the workshop with a sense of agency over my own sound and vocal feeling that two years of very good Linklater training did not inspire in me. I have very simple tools that I can use daily, and if today’s workshop is any indicator, they are as profound as they are easy to do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that the workshop is currently free of charge, there’s no reason not to try it out. Even if you consider yourself “a serious actor” who would “never dare do a musical,” there is a massive lesson to be learned from Jon’s work and his philosophy, not to mention you’ll have a lot of fun and feel great about yourself. In the days following the workshop, I’ve been inspired to really explore and have fun with my voice, rather than just try and “develop” it along more conventional metrics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information about the workshop, you can check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://theatergym.com/classes.html&quot;&gt;www.theatergym.com/classes.html&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any other questions or comments feel free to reach out to tim@brashpursuits.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/02/15/sing-a-secret.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/02/15/sing-a-secret.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Recommendations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Due To Events: A Play I'm Commanding You To See</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we talk about a piece of experimental theater, it’s often helpful to identify what the experiment is. After all, how can we judge a work’s success if we don’t know what it’s actually trying to achieve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Human Head’s new play Due To Events, I can only assume the experiment is something like “How many times can a human being laugh in an hour and a half before their head completely explodes?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The darkly comic journey of one woman (Anne Gridley) and one cat (Laura Campbell) through an interminable period of house arrest is, from its opening moments onward, remarkably funny. Aided (and annoyed) on their journey by a bumbling lawyer (Ben Beckley) and a sinister food delivery man (David Skeist, who also provides voice-over narration), the duo slowly descend into the kind of madness that can only be visited in this kind of theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give away any more of the form of the show would be spoiling part of what makes it so much fun to watch, so instead I’ll talk about the four actors and how great they are, because you could do your graduate’s thesis on the acting in this show and still want to keep talking about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the moments the play begins, David Skeist takes us by the hand and eagerly drags us into the show’s metaphysical space. He assures us with his mannerisms that there will be plenty to laugh about. But his words, spoken with the kind of veracity that the rest of us can only aspire to, are foreboding somehow. And it’s that sense of foreboding that, no matter how funny the play ever gets, never leaves.  The fact that Skeist can make the play’s peppering of late night radio-esque soliloquys about existential pain as funny as they are anxiety-inducing is the kind of speaking we come to the theater hoping we’ll hear. His various turns as incidental bit characters also glue the comedy of the play together impeccably. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura Campbell plays a cat. And she does it so well you have to wonder after a certain point if she isn’t ACTUALLY a cat who has somehow come into ownership of a human form that is capable of every subtlety and explosion of movement one could ask for onstage. Rather than simply watching an actor go through the motions of an animal exercise, we’re seeing something olympic happening. If the text of the show ever loses you in its dreamy metaphysics, it doesn’t take long for the cat to do something insane. The movements of the role are so deftly performed it’s almost like watching Chaplin or Buster Keaton in real life. Only they’re trapped inside a David Lynch movie. Or something. And in case seeing an actor flawlessly embody a cat onstage wasn’t enough for you, she talks. It’s great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben Beckley’s turn as a hapless lawyer gives us someone in the play who is as confused as we are. He tries to do his job right, but it sends him on a globetrotting quest of vignettes where he never quite manages to fit in or say the right thing, no matter what locale he’s in. In a play full of philosophy and smart ideas, farces and wild jokes, it helps to have someone who can’t quite cope with it all. His ability to keep a straight face and go with exactly whatever he’s doing regardless of how much the audience is laughing is astounding, especially since he was only about eight feet away from me on one of his first entrances and I was laughing so hard I thought they might kick me out of the theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anne Gridley plays Hero, the woman exiled to her living room on account of court proceedings that do not seem to be going particularly well. Anne’s ability to let us see her character’s descent in pure gradient, rather than through carefully studied dramatic beats, allows us to never know exactly how mad she’s gone, and consequently how mad we might be for thinking she’s still sane. If there is anything I hate more than actors “playing crazy,” I don’t know what it is, and the fact that Anne never gives us a straight answer or shows us how we should feel about her outright makes the play infinitely more of an exciting puzzle to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what makes the play so much more fun than more standard theatrical fare. It plays with various levels of audience engagement, making us want to figure out how things will develop by dangling the narrative string in front of us and making us chase it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The play also oozes atmosphere, with an eerie set designed by Sara Walsh, and lighting by Simon Harding. Chris Chappell provides an underscore of jazz, ambient, and experiential sounds that really excite me for the possibilities of sound design for the stage. David Lynch’s best works come alive due in no small part to Angelo Badalamenti’s sound work, and Chris Chappell’s work here help underscore the laughs with that intangible creepy crawly feeling in much the same way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When watching a play this impeccably acted, it’s hard to talk about the writing and the directing, because so much of the experience seems like the actors are four geniuses coming up with it all on the spot. Given the smooth operation of the whole show, one can barely imagine how it was all written down in the first place, and it’s even tougher to imagine what the process of putting it on stage was like. It’s truly the kind of magical experience that we can only arrive at in the theater, and we have to be grateful to Jean Ann Douglass and Eric John Meyer for giving it to us without any creative reservations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes the difficult easy, and turns the existential howling to laughter. A must see if ever there was one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DUE TO EVENTS runs at The Brick Theater in Brooklyn until February 27th. For more information about the play and Human Head Performance Group visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humanheadperformancegroup.com/&quot;&gt;www.humanheadperformancegroup.com&lt;/a&gt;. For any inquiries about this article, reach out to tim@brashpursuits.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/02/12/due-to-events.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/02/12/due-to-events.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jim Jarrett &amp; The Meisner Technique Studio</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this, odds are you’ve encountered the Meisner Technique in one form or another. A lot of great actors have put it to incredible use, and Meisner himself is, it goes without saying, an absolute legend in the world of acting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own personal journey with the Meisner Technique is a varied and problematic one. I’ve studied under multiple teachers, a few good, a few bad, and one or two incredible enough to actually deserve the title. I find Meisner to be quite possibly the most perfect acting teacher ever available to us, the only problem being, he’s not around anymore. And a lot of his students, for better or worse, loved him enough to vehemently claim his name for their own, regardless of how qualified they are to do so. There’s a lot of in-fighting about what the technique is and what it isn’t, and many a teacher will tell you that “their version” of Meisner is “the truth.” To be frank, I’ve encountered more ego in my Meisner classes than I’ve encountered pretty much anywhere else. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today though, I’d like to share with you a Meisner teacher who’s doing things right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I can’t speak to Jim Jarrett’s flesh and blood, brick and mortar class room experience. He teaches out of San Francisco. I live in New York. We’ve never had a conversation. But, he has managed to do something that has caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;He has decided to give away part of himself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charting a course towards becoming an actor is one of the most daringly personal journeys a person can make. You’re offering yourself up to the eyes of other people. Sure, you might end up cashing million dollar paychecks to do it, but you also might not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it means something to me when an acting teacher is willing to minister to the disciples free of charge. The smallest advice, given at no personal gain for the giver, is a form of currency we don’t have enough of in the acting world. Everybody seems to want to keep the path a secret. Probably out of fear that you’ll realize they don’t actually have any idea where it was to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim Jarrett offers a free newsletter and scores of engaging videos which are an invaluable resource for actors at any level. Time and thought are put into these missives, and they’re both inspiring and educational. Trust me, I don’t go in for spam-based bullshit meant to sell me something. Ever. Jim is cutting through all that and using the internet for its purest function: delivering worthwhile thoughts and learning points to people who can use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So go forth, and use them eagerly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can check out more about Jim Jarrett, his newsletter, videos, and classes at &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20160114193126/http://themeisnertechniquestudio.com/&quot;&gt;www.themeisnertechniquestudio.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;If you have any questions, comments, or inquiries about this article, please shoot an email to tim@brashpursuits.com. Have a great day!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/01/31/jim-jarrett-meisner-technique.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/01/31/jim-jarrett-meisner-technique.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Recommendations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Going To ESPAFest?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this world, there are very few perfect places. If you read my &lt;a href=&quot;/recommendations/2015/12/13/why-you-should-be-going-to-espa.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; about ESPA, you know I believe at least one exists. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m stoked to announce that if you live in New York City and you’re still on the fence about going to ESPA, a week full of free classes and events is just around the corner, including a free Alexander Workshop with &lt;a href=&quot;/recommendations/2015/12/15/mentor-spotlight-karen-braga.html&quot;&gt;Karen Braga&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favorite people of all time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get all the details over on the ESPA official &lt;a href=&quot;http://primarystages.org/espa/our-community/espafest&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and I highly encourage you to take part. If nothing else, you can come see me fall flat on my face in another gorgeous night of one act plays at DETENTION #32. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have any questions about the ESPA experience, feel free to email me at tim@brashpursuits.com, although I honestly encourage you to swing in and see what things are like for yourself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/01/30/are-you-going-to-espafest.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/recommendations/2017/01/30/are-you-going-to-espafest.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Recommendations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I Learned Working on Green Screen for the First Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About a month or two ago I shot a film with the youth outreach program Mythic Bridge, in collaboration with the Boy Scouts of America. While I could probably write an entire novel about how necessary I think Mythic Bridge is as a structure in the film community, I’m focusing here today on a particular opportunity that I had while working with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before that day of shooting, I had never been on green screen before.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/147924858&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can watch the video above and tell pretty clearly what I was asked to do on green screen. I won’t vouch for the quality of my performance. Everyone involved (including the kids) was much more talented than I am, and I feel overwhelmingly lucky to have been a part of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I learned certain things that day that will greatly help my career going forward, as no classroom I’ve ever been in has even remotely addressed the question of acting in the age of CGI. It’s easy to write off the performances in comic book and blockbuster action movies as “easy” or “dumb.” But try acting on green screen once or twice, and you’ll suddenly realize how much those actors really sell everything, regardless of the fact that they only have the script and their imaginations to work with in a lot of scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with another actor provides its own list of challenges: listening, responding, etc. etc. These are things you could drill in a Meisner program for two or three years and still not get right. But what do you do when the other actor you’re working with is supposed to be a giant tree, or an alien super soldier, or… I don’t know, a spaceship? How can you create a believable and human performance in the face of the pure technical vacuum needed to facilitate CGI? Well…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Be Willing To Look Very Stupid. &lt;/strong&gt;Review any behind the scenes footage of any movie since Lord Of The Rings and you’ll admit that the actors occasionally look very, very goofy in actuality. You’ll sometimes be asked to do things that might not make any sense in the moment, but you can rest assured that somewhere, some technical wizard will spin whatever you do into filmic gold. I spent the first 10-20 minutes of our allotted green screen hour just getting over the nerves of people watching me flail about like a moron. Get over yourself, and give them whatever they want. Which leads me to…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Trust More. &lt;/strong&gt;It’s not always easy to take every note, to make every adjustment, or to justify every character decision. Actors everywhere, myself included, have a tendency to hold onto “character decisions,” “beats,” and “moments.” But in these instances of intensive CGI, you have to trust that pretty much everybody else knows how it’ll turn out a lot better than you do. Do what they tell you, when they tell you, and don’t overthink it. You’re in a scene that is primarily a visual composition, not a “raw” acting moment. Trust what people see from the outside, and be willing to paint their picture. I.E…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Go All Out. &lt;/strong&gt;I’m big into naturalistic acting. I hate watching people send a moment sailing way over the top, especially if they don’t have any emotional core to back it up. But, if there’s any time to give it your all and go soaring past all the walls, it’s when you’re in front of a green screen. The subtle reactions in character-to-character scenes simply don’t work as well when you’re supposed to be reacting to a 100 foot tall version of yourself inside a video game. Like, not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Let The World Carry You. &lt;/strong&gt;You’re standing in front of a green tarp, or maybe the room is painted green. You might even have a mo-cap suit on. In a certain sense, this can become the least imaginative position an actor can find themselves in. You have nothing but yourself to hook you in. BUT, that means that ultimately, you can imagine the world around you. You can see anything you want, and as long as you react to it, a ton of other geniuses (who work a lot harder than you do) will fill it in later with whatever they actually want. Make your job as easy as possible, and it will make theirs easier too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, I’m still fairly new at this, so this is one of the places where I’m really not going to act like I know what I’m talking about. But watching this film back with the special effects all in place, I can immediately identify a few ways I could’ve done my own job better, especially given how much everyone else knocked this thing out of the park. A lot of it comes down to self-consciousness, and the misconception that I have to take my job “seriously” in order to do good work. Lighten up, give it your all, and commit fully to being one hand in building an insane world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information about Mythic Bridge, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mythicbridge.org/&quot;&gt;www.mythicbridge.org&lt;/a&gt;. The CGI in the above short was created by Mo Caicedo, a genius among men. You can check out more of his work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mocaicedo.com/&quot;&gt;www.mocaicedo.com&lt;/a&gt;. For any other complaints, concerns, or questions, fire off an email to tim@brashpursuits.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/28/what-i-learned-working-on-green-screen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/28/what-i-learned-working-on-green-screen.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
